# **JAMES FAYE**

Address: 85 Pikes Lane, Glossop, SK13 8ED

**Phone:** 07763856888

Email: jameswrfaye@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

With 6 years of industry experience, I am a driven and ambitious professional known for delivering high-quality features as a Product Manager at Gamma. From strategy and concept through to delivery, I stay close to stakeholders, using their feedback and insights to ensure that we deliver real value and solve real problems. I have a wealth of experience in different organisations and sectors, and across the product lifecycle.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Product Manager, Gamma (SmartAgent & SmartPCI B2B SaaS)

Apr 2023 - Present

- Created and managed the **SmartAgent** and **SmartPCI** product roadmap, leading 3 development teams across different geographic locations.
- Curated all Agile ceremonies Retrospectives, Stand-ups, Refinement sessions, and Show-and-Tell at the end of our 2-week sprint cycles.
- Prioritised the Product Roadmap based on value and costs, ensuring optimal allocation of resources and minimal impact on our product's reputation.
- Created, designed, and led the implementation of many scalable and secure product features:
  - CRM integrations with Zendesk, Salesforce, and MS Dynamics.
  - Al auto-generated After Call Work forms using AWS Bedrock and Lambda, saving our oldest customer approximately £1.5 million annually.
  - Led the end-to-end development and launch of SmartPCI on AWS Marketplace, a PCI DSS Level 1 compliant payment solution for Amazon Connect, enabling secure card payments across voice and digital channels.
  - Enhanced supervisor screens of Agent and Queue performance using AWS APIs to create a bespoke performance view, reducing customer spend on AWS services by removing dependencies on Redis and OpenSearch.
- Improved the App release process through the introduction of more readable Release Notes and a Community Page with how-to guides and support FAQs.
- Line Manager for a Product Owner and Business Analyst, supporting their growth and development while ensuring both stayed up-to-date with the latest product trends and AWS roadmap.
- Acted as the Product contact for our largest customer, ensuring our roadmap aligned with theirs and serving as a point of escalation for any concerns.

## Product Owner, Gamma (Formerly known as Mission Labs)

Apr 2022 - Apr 2023

- Led wider workshops using Miro between business stakeholders, solution architects, engineering, and other key stakeholders, fostering a collaborative environment and ensuring alignment throughout the product development lifecycle.
- Wrote business requirements and translated them into User stories for our development teams.
- Worked closely with our Product Manager to prioritise and ensure delivery of product features for our Webchat solution.
- Collaborated with UX designers to create wireframes and prototypes, refining user experiences based on stakeholder feedback.
- Conducted competitor analysis to identify opportunities for enhancing our Webchat product and maintaining a competitive edge.
- Maintained and updated the product backlog, ensuring alignment with business goals and technical feasibility.
- Supported the release process by writing release notes and conducting demos for internal and external stakeholders.

- Led the COVID-19 rebate project in Operations, orchestrating the implementation of a £125 million rebate program across all insurance customers, providing financial relief during the pandemic.
- Successfully managed multiple cross-functional projects, ensuring delivery within scope, budget, and timelines.
- Coordinated with internal teams and external vendors to define project requirements and deliverables.
- Monitored project progress using Agile and Waterfall methodologies, providing regular updates to stakeholders through reports and presentations.
- Identified and mitigated risks to maintain project momentum and address potential roadblocks proactively.
- Aligned stakeholders through effective communication strategies, enabling smooth project execution.
- Deployed and increased Webchat across all of BUPA UK Insurance using Agile methodology, acting as ScrumMaster to drive continuous improvement and achieved the following results.
  - Increased chat volume by 33% during Q3 of 2021 through redirection of calls and promotional activity on SMS messages.
- Reduced AHT (Average Handling Time) by 3 minutes during 2021 through root cause workshops, user interviews and data analysis on Excel.

## **Operations Management Graduate, Bupa UK Insurance**

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

- Navigated through diverse operational functions, absorbing business and insurance knowledge, whilst leveraging this understanding to streamline processes within the contact centre.
- Managed a team of 10 contact centre agents, achieving a 23% increase in first-call resolution rate and a 17% reduction in average handling time, resulting in boosted customer experience.
- Planned and collaborated with The First Word, a training agency, to grow letter writing skills of customer relations staff (75 FTE) at Bupa.
  - This Improved first-time resolution rates and empathy scores (from 54 to 83 points in six months).

InTouch, Founder Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

(A mobile app designed to bridge the gap digitally between players and coaches.)

- Generating leads and communicating with clients. For example, our first client was Bristol university rugby team, I liaised with the head coach Joe Goodman took him for a coffee and we talked about the app as a concept and he trialled it for us.
  - PR through YENA (Young Entrepreneurs Networking Association). We communicated with the founder of the organisation called Ash and we made a brief pitch about our company at one of their networking events.

## **EDUCATION**

**Degree - Bachelor of Business Management with Honours (1st Class)** 

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Hard Skills:

3 years AWS, Serverless, Unit Testing, Product Management, Platform Thinking, Decisioning Infrastructure, Experimentation & A/B Testing, SQL, Data Analytics, Figma, Facilitation of workshops, Process Mapping (Visio), PCI Compliance, Payment Gateways, Cloud Computing, Feature Development, Release Management, Roadmapping, Technical Scoping, B2B2C Platforms, MS Office, Presenting, Jira/Confluence.

#### Soft Skills:

Leadership, Stakeholder Management, Agile Processes, Mentorship/Coaching, Strategic Thinking, Decision-making, Root Cause Analysis, Problem Solving, Prioritisation, Communication (Structured & Persuasive), Cross-functional Collaboration, Management, Business Strategy, Curiosity & Adaptability.

#### **Personal Interests:**

I created a touch rugby club in Manchester called the Manchester Foxes. I also represented my country in the home World Cup, placing 5th overall in the world.